Andy Humes

Denver, CO 80206 humes.andrew@gmail.com 614-975-7115

Professional Summary

Determined, junior level coder versed in many coding languages with proficiency in the front end frameworks. Offers a unique adaptability, stemming from a heavy background in technical skills, complex systems, and analysis. Strong customer service background from many years in health care

Skills

- React
- HTML/CSS
- Node
- MongoDB
- Handlebars
- Heroku

- JavaScript
- Express
- MySql
- Bootstrap
- Github

Experience

Certified Ophthalmic Technician Colorado Cataract and Laser, LLC

Jan 2022 - Current

Aurora, CO

- Completed ophthalmic testing procedures to assess patients' current functionality.
- Utilized Electronic Practice Management (EPM) and Electronic Health Records (EHR) software to record and document patients' medical history, complaints, and concerns.
- Conducted diagnostic assessments to help ophthalmologists make skilled assessments.

Clinical Research Coordinator

May 2019 - Nov 2021

Colorado Eye Consultants

Littleton, CO

- Managed documentation, including clinical research data worksheets, shared drive, clinical research files, and Electronic Data Capture (EDC).
- Maintained research data, patient fields, regulatory binders and study databases for organization and quick reference.
- Screened potential subjects, reviewed medical records and discussed histories with physicians to determine subject eligibility.
- Continuously monitored studies to verify compliance with protocols and regulatory standards, ensuring compliance with legal standards.

Ocular Genetics Coordinator

Jul 2014 - Jan 2019

Colorado Retina Associates

Denver, CO

• Developed an electrodiagnostic eye laboratory and performed the tests, bringing what would be outside referrals to on-site appointments.

- Arranged low-vision and accessibility services with local providers.
- Ensured that the clinic environment and our documentation was compatible with accessibility requirements
- Coordinated academic and research activities including paper writing, database management, and statistics.

Research Assistant - Biotechnology

Oct 2009 - Feb 2014

SomaLogic, Inc. Mitomics, Inc. The US Bureau of Reclamation. Ohio State University.

Boulder, CO

- Performed experiments at the lab bench in a variety of disciplines, including molecular biology, genetics, biochemistry, and microbiology.
- Kept meticulous records and analyzed massive sets of data, especially focused on genetics, using Laboratory Information Systems (LIMS).
- Performed statistical analysis. Presented research updates to small groups

Education

Certificate of Completion : Full Stack Software Development	<i>May 2022</i>
University of Denver	Denver, CO
Master of Biomedical Science	Jun 2013
Colorado State University	Fort Collins, CO
Bachelor of Science: Molecular Biology	Jun 2008
The Ohio State University	Columbus, OH
Bachelor of Arts: Anthropology	Jun 2008
The Ohio State University	Columbus, OH

Community Service

- The Foundation Fighting Blindness Chapter Leader and Professional Outreach Chair -2014-present
- True Independence Secretary 2014-present

Publications

EyeNet Magazine - Feature: May, 2018

• Inherited Retinal Diseases: Redefining Patient Care.

Retina Today - October, 2018

• A Simplified Technique for In-Office Tap and Injection for Endophthalmitis